# Elena Gutiérrez Viedma

Website



24 (November 10, 1993) Age Place of birth Madrid, Spain **Nationality** Spanish Email elena.gutierrez@imdea.org

Address **IMDEA Software Institute** Office 342 Campus de Montegancedo s/n 28223 - Pozuelo de Alarcón Madrid, Spain http://software.imdea.org/~elena.gutierrez/

### **About Me**

I am a third-year Ph.D. student at the IMDEA Software Institute in Madrid, under the supervision of Prof. Pierre Ganty. Before, I have a Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science at Universidad Autónoma de Madrid. During my summer breaks, I have enjoyed three research internships at IMDEA Software working with Ganty on formal verification of programs using Horn clauses.

Now, my research interests are mainly focused in the theory of formal languages and automata and its applications to software verification. I am also interested in Horn clause verification, and logic and functional programming.

# **Research Experience**

**IMDEA Software Institute** Sept. 2016 - present

PhD. in Software, Systems and Computing supervised by Prof. Pierre Ganty

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

**IMDEA Software Institute** Sept. 2015 - Feb. 2016

Bachelor's Project supervised by Prof. Pierre Ganty

2013 - 2015 **IMDEA Software Institute** 

Three-month research summer internships

## Education

2011-2016 Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science (360 ECTS)

Universidad Autónoma de Madrid | Average Grade (out of 10) - 8.21

#### **Publications**

2018 The Parikh Property for Weighted Context-Free Grammars

P. Ganty and E. Gutiérrez. FSTTCS 2018

2017 Parikh Image of Pushdown Automata

P. Ganty and E. Gutiérrez. FCT 2017

# **Bachelor's Project**

2016 Linearisation of Index Bounded Sets of Horn Clauses.

Supervised by Prof. Pierre Ganty

This thesis presents a Prolog algorithm that transforms non-linear logic programs into linear

preserving their meaning Grade (out of 10) - 10

### Schools/Seminars Attended

- Microsoft Research PhD. Summer School. 4–8, July, 2016. Cambridge, UK.
- 2<sup>nd</sup> School on Formal Verification by The Hebrew University. 17–21, December, 2017. Jerusalem, Israel.
- womENcourage 2018, ACM Celebration of Women in Computing. 3–5, October, 2018. Belgrade, Serbia.

#### **Conference/Public Talks**

March, 2017 Parikh Image of Pushdown Automata
S3, Seminar Series at Imdea Software Institute. March 7<sup>th</sup>, 2017

Sept., 2017 Parikh Image of Pushdown Automata
Presentation at FCT 2017 in Bordeaux, France. September 11<sup>th</sup>, 2017

April, 2018 Weighted Context-Free Grammars: Does Parikh's Theorem still hold?
S3, Seminar Series at Imdea Software Institute. April 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2018

Sept., 2018 The Parikh Property for Weighted Context-Free Grammars
Formal Methods and Verification Seminar at the Université Libre de Bruxelles. September 26<sup>th</sup>, 2018

# Languages

**Spanish** Native

**English** Fluent TOEFL iBT (Feb. 2016). Total (out of 120): 104

French Basic

# **Programing Languages**

• Prolog, Haskell, C, Python, ŁTĘX

### **Grants**

2017-2021 Predoctoral Contract for PhD. Training Grant (FPI)

Provided by the Spanish Ministry of Economy, Industry and Competitiveness

#### **Additional Information**

**Teaching Experience** Support classes for students at secondary education

Mathematics, English, Physics and Chemistry

**Volunteer work** International exchange organization AFS

Coordination of exchange activities for foreign students in Spain

Soñar Despierto Foundation

Support classes for students coming from marginalized backgrounds